Ankit Rane Frontend Developer

📧 anks.rane@gmail.com | 🌐 ankitrane.netlify.app | 📱 +91 80824 66900 | 📍 Mumbai, India

Summary

Detail-oriented and skilled front-end developer with 4+ years of experience building responsive and user-centered web applications. Familiar with React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, and AJAX. Experienced in building efficient single-page applications (SPA), performance optimization, cross-browser compatibility, and responsive design with Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS. Team-based and collaborative with experience in agile, and API integrations.

Professional Experience

•

Frontend Developer Dec 2022 - Present

- Created responsive, cross-browser compatible web pages utilizing React.js, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Transformed PSD and wireframes into pixel-perfect web pages.
- Created dynamic, single-page applications with React.js, AJAX, form validation, and real-time data processing.
- Integrated RESTful APIs using back-end developers to connect the data with real-time data.

Here Technologies Pvt Ltd

Airoli, Mumbai

Mumbai

GIS Analyst (Partial Front-End Development)

SPAAN IT Solutions Pvt Ltd (Client: R K Swamy)

June 2019 - December 2022

- Analyzed and enhanced geospatial data for Highly Automated Driving (HAD) project.
- Developed and supported the internal dashboards and UI components using HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- Worked with teams to integrate GIS data into web platforms.
- A variety of JavaScript libraries were used for visualizing the spatial data.

Techflux Vashi, Mumbai

Software Developer

January 2018–July 2018

• Developed web apps using Bubble.io, and customized the components with HTML, CSS and JavaScript as needed.

Ankit Rane Frontend Developer

Abhay Tech Solutions LLP

Marol, Mumbai

Internship Trainee (Technical Writer)

July 2017 – September 2017

• Created UML diagrams and contributed to project documentation for software development teams.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering – Computer Engineering

June 2014 - May 2017

Mumbai University 5.88 CGPI

Diploma in Computer Technology

June 2010 - April 2014

Shreeram Polytechnic, Airoli 62.26%

S.S.C. June 2001 - March 2010

S.V. Joshi High School, Dombivli

77.09%

Technical Skills, Frameworks and Tools

- Front-End Technologies: React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), ¡Query, AJAX, JSON, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks & Libraries: Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React Router
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- **Development Tools:** Webpack, NPM
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum
- Soft Skills: Problem-solving, Communication, Team Collaboration, Time Management

Projects

G20 (https://www.motherofdemocracyg20.com)

Created a multi-language site that displayed Indian culture in the spirit of global democracy projects before the G20 Summit.

Technologies HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, XML

Ankit Rane Frontend Developer

Gmmco (https://www.gmmco.in/)

Gmmco, inc.'s corporate site with an emphasis on user experience and accessibility that showcases Gmmco's extensive inventory of construction and mining machines, product solutions, and services while allowing customers to easily navigate the site and renew.

Technologies React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tailwind

Vijay Tanks (https://vijaytanks.com/)

Created and managed a website for Vijay Tanks, a global industrial engineering firm in the energy sector. The website presents their various offerings of storage tanks and process equipment.

Technologies HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Birla Locator (https://www.birlaa1.com/birla-a1-dealer-locator.php/https://www.birlaa1.com/birla-a1-locator-construction-expert.php)

Designed a dealer locator tool for Birla A1 using Google Maps, which allows users to easily locate dealer of Birla product category across India.

Technologies HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, iOuerv

Stockholding (https://www.stockholding.com)

Built a web application that includes providing financial planning, wealth management and investment solutions for a large financial services corporation.

Technologies HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Zuari FarmHub (https://zuarifarmhub.com/)

Created and maintained a site for Zuari FarmHub, a leading provider of agricultural solutions. Such as permitting visitors to review their extensive portfolio of agri-inputs including fertilizers, seeds, and crop protection products. In addition, sites articulate their dedication and utilising innovative and sustainable farming methods, with an agri-input strategy to empower farmers.

Technologies JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap